ILGWU Local 48 Records 5780/040
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 48 Records
1926-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 48
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/040
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Records.
The collection contains records of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 48, Italian Cloakmakers Union, including minutes of membership and Executive Board meetings, files on elections, notes, and correspondence.
5489877
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, August 14, 2003
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 48 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Italian Cloakmakers' Union, was chartered by members of Local 1 and Local 35 in 1916 and based in New York, New York. As membership and industry declined in the 1970s, the local became Local 48 United Coat, Suit and Allied Garment Workers' Union of Brooklyn, Queens and Staten Island (coat and suit workers in all crafts in Brooklyn, Queens and Staten Island), and later Local 48 Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers Union of North Brooklyn. In late 1981, the Joint Board approved a measure to dissolve Local 48, and Local 89 was renamed Local 89-48 to honor the historic significance of the Italian cloakmakers.
Scope and Contents
Much of the collection is composed of minutes of the Executive Board. There are also minutes of the Membership meetings. All of the meeting minutes are in Italian.
Material appearing in English includes cases before the Appeal Committee, notes and correspondence. There is substantial information on local elections, including lists of candidates for upcoming elections, nominations, and rejection notices to candidates informing them they are not qualified to run. The Examination and Objection Committee was to consider the qualifications of officers who were 65 and candidates in upcoming elections to determine their health and if they could perform their job.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/041: ILGWU New York Cloak Joint Board Payroll Analysis 5780/040 mf: ILGWU Local 48 Executive Board Minutes on Microfilm 6036/102 P: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Photographs 6036/102 MB: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Memorabilia 6036/102m: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Files 6036/102 PUBS: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Publications
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 48 (New York, N.Y.)
5489877
- Cases, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dinner in Honor of Molisani, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  English and Italian
- Elections, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Elections, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Elections, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Election- Examination and Objection Committee, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Election- Examination and Objection Committee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Italian Labor Center, 1926-1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Monteodorisio (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Trip to Italy, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Local 48 Notes and Correspondence [folder 1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Local 48 Notes and Correspondence [folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Fourth Section Minutes, 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 3], 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Italian
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 3], 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 3], 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 3], 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 3], 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 3], 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Misc. Administrative Documents [Italian] (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 3], 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 3], 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 3], 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Primo Distretto Sessione, 1929-1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Membership Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Membership Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 4], 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 4], 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 4], 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 4 of 4], 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 3], 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 3], 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 3], 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 3], 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 3], 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 3 of 3], 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Executive Board Minutes and Membership, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)